foreign
[Music]
welcome back to actual English I'm
Jennifer Clyde it's time for lesson 146
and let's begin a brand new category
let's shift over to Spring weather that
is of course you and I we all have our
favorite Seasons which season
is your favorite season
now my favorite season is the summer
season of course Spring is nice fall is
nice and winter is nice and I love the
snow about the winter season but I
cannot tolerate I cannot bear the
freezing cold temperatures of the winter
that's why since I don't get hot easily
and I love the sun summer is my favorite
but spring and fall alike are yes very
nice Seasons I mean it's the best time
to get out there enjoy outdoor
activities especially after The Long
Winter Spring finally comes and
everyone's so excited but there is one
problem
well unfortunately some people are very
sensitive to pollen for example and some
people have respiratory problems so for
those people spring may not be the best
season of all four seasons you may
suffer from things such as hay fever
hives even we'll talk about that today
and these things may cause allergic
reactions pollen that's floating around
in the air you may end up sneezing all
the time and just uh crying or you may
have a runny nose you may have an itch
here and there and continuously scratch
your arm or your hand or your whole body
so for some people it's very difficult
to Bear the spring weather especially
because of allergies so let's talk about
that today here we begin with actual
talk
foreign
[Music]
I can't tell you how happy I am to see
winter going oh me too I hate winter
especially in Korea because Korea is
like a country of extremes you know in
the winter it is freezing cold and in
the summer it's baking hot Autumn and
spring they're so short but they're my
favorites oh tell me about it well for
me it's kind of a love-hate relationship
with spring because that's when my
allergies attack oh have you got hay
fever no actually I'm a bit of a weird
case here
um this is gonna sound weird but every
year I suffer from really bad allergies
and yet every time I take an allergy
test my doctor can't figure out what it
is that's causing my hives or my
problems I know but I'm willing to live
with it if it means that I can
comfortably jog outside enjoy the cherry
blossoms and enjoy the beauty of Korean
spring yeah the spring here is so
beautiful but I'm the same as you I
suffer from allergies but I got hay
fever so I know what it is at least
um I heard that's pretty nasty yeah I
have to take my antihistamines every day
like when it's pollen season and things
like that but I found that less people
in Korea suffer with hay fever than in
the UK like I reckon out of my friends
about half suffer with hay fever but
here not many people do so they didn't
really sympathize with me when my nose
is running or my eyes are itching I
sympathize
I need it really I did I'm sorry for you
but do you like doing things outdoors
then in the spring because the winter
you can barely do anything oh yeah I
love jogging you know what I just like
going for walks it's so beautiful and
there's so much to see and that's a cool
thing about living in a city is that you
never get tired because there's always a
new neighborhood to visit right that's
true yeah and I love being outdoors and
exercising because I hate the gym I have
a growth against the gym because I don't
have cabin fever yeah I don't like
sweating with a load of other people so
spring gives me the opportunity to just
get into The Great Outdoors and breathe
some fresh air yeah cheers to Spring
absolutely come on foreign
okay welcome back everyone that was
today's actual talk conversation between
Peter and Kelly now Kelly's mentioned
something about how she is sensitive or
she becomes sensitive to certain things
whenever spring comes but whenever she
goes to the doctor her doctor says Uh
there's nothing wrong with you but what
about Peter hmm he's mentioned something
about hay fever so because of his
allergies spring is of course not his
favorite season let's uh check out what
they've mentioned in today's actual talk
conversation here we go first of all
Kelly says I can't tell you how happy I
am to see winter going so here we go
we're saying bye bye winter hello spring
and uh Peter says oh me too I hate
winter
why especially in Korea because Korea is
like a country of extremes okay Korea is
a country of extremes now if you see
extremes what are you talking about
notice there is an s
okay we're talking about extremes so
when you want to say that something is
very different from one another
you want to say extremes so perhaps
Peter is talking about the weather it's
very cold and it's very hot spring and
winter okay so Korea is a country of
extremes
the winter it's freezing cold
and the summer is baking hot
I hope we have a chance in the future to
talk about temperatures or um yeah when
it comes to food or even the temperature
when you want to talk about the winter
season you can say it's very cold but
even better freezing cold you feel like
you are going to freeze okay so Winters
in Korea are freezing cold what about
Summers the summer is baking hot hmm
we bake bread for example and when we
put bread or dough in the oven we bake
it with what
heat so if you see something is baking
hot it means it is very very hot so
summers in Korea are baking hot they're
sizzling hot Autumn and spring they are
so short but they are my favorites he
says
okay so now we know that Peter he does
not really like winter he hates winter
as a matter of fact summers are okay but
Summers are too hot they're baking hot
and his favorite Seasons happen to be
Autumn and spring fall and spring
now Kelly says oh tell me about it what
does she mean when she says this oh tell
me about it you would say this to
somebody
that you agree with if somebody says
something to you and you totally 100
percent agree with him or her you can
say oh yeah tell me about it yes I agree
with you well for me she says
it's kind of a love-hate relationship
with spring because that's when my
allergies attack
here we go love hate relationship love
hate
love hate consists of words Love and
Hate
so a love-hate relationship is a
relationship involving both feelings of
love and hate so if you really love
something but really hate it at the same
time you can say that it is a love hate
something so she's talking about how
spring is kind of a love-hate
relationship for her because what that's
when my allergies attack ah
so she has a hard time during spring
season
now Peter says oh you've got hay fever I
did mention hay fever earlier on hay
fever is a seasonal allergic condition
okay and usually it's caused by pollen
that's floating up in the air so your
eyes may water and you may have itches
all over as well but what does she say
she says no
actually this is going to sound weird
it's going to sound strange but every
year
every single year I suffer from really
bad allergies so you can suffer from
something right suffer from something an
illness or hear bad allergies she has
difficulty because of her allergies but
yet every time I take an allergy test
my doctor cannot figure out what it is
that causing my hives or my problems so
we're talking about hay fever and even
hives now hives is an allergic reaction
to food or even substances so if you eat
food that has for example peanuts in it
and you're allergic to peanuts you can
break out into a hive into hives so your
skin swells up it becomes really red and
it itches so it's an allergic reaction
so she's saying that she's very
sensitive to something during the Spring
season but whenever she goes to get an
allergy test her doctor says hmm I don't
know what's wrong I don't know what's
causing your hives or your problems he
cannot figure it out he has no idea why
okay and then of course Peter says hmm
that's odd meaning that's strange
now Kelly says I know but I am willing
to
live with it
if it means I can comfortably jog
outside
enjoy the cherry blossoms
and enjoy the beauty of spring
okay let's take a look at this one long
sentence okay so obviously she has a
difficult time during spring season
because of her allergies or whatever it
is that's causing all these problems but
she says I am willing to live with it
live with it what does that mean it
simply means to accept it okay except
the difficulties
Just Go With It continue on with your
life and not worry about it not let it
stop you so hey I'll just accept it I'll
just live with it if it means I can
comfortably jog outside enjoy the cherry
blossoms and enjoy the beauty of Korean
spring if it means so here she's saying
as long as I could enjoy the cherry
blossoms the beauty of Korean spring and
also enjoy a jog outside whenever I want
to go for a run
now Peter says yeah the spring here here
meaning in Korea is so beautiful but I
am the same as you he says I suffer from
allergies but I've got hay fever he says
so hay fever I did mention too it is a
seasonal allergic condition okay so if
you're sensitive to Airborne pollen and
certain substances like dust in the air
you may have hay fever
now Kelly says I heard that it is pretty
nasty
nasty this is a word you might have
heard of it's slime it's informal nasty
has several definitions here she's
saying that I heard that it is hay fever
is nasty meaning it is terrible oh it's
very difficult to deal with but nasty
can also mean ugly it can also mean
dirty for example okay so this word has
many different definitions but here
she's saying that it is very difficult
to deal with okay
moving on yeah I've got to take
antihistamines these are drugs okay that
can cure uh
allergies or even a cold so he has to
take medication every day when it's
pollen season
pollen season spring season or any other
season where there's pollen in the air
but I found that less or even better
fewer people in Korea suffer with hay
fever than in the UK so fewer people in
Korea
suffer with hay fever then in the UK
like I reckon out of my friends about
half
suffer with hay fever
but here not many people do so what is
he saying he's talking about hay fever
how more people in the UK suffer with
hay fever compared to people in Korea
now the word here is reckon reckon I
reckon I reckon that something reckon
means to consider think perhaps okay
we'll practice reckon pronunciation and
we'll go over some synonyms as well so
now you have an idea of what he is
saying right okay moving on he says so
they don't really sympathize
with me when my nose is running
and my eyes are itching
so this is a continuation of what Peter
was talking about he was talking about
hay fever and how not as many Koreans
suffer with hay fever compared to people
in the UK and even his friends so he's
saying people don't really know how
difficult it is people don't really
sympathize with me when my nose is
running and my eyes are itching so
sympathize with someone what does that
mean it means to share that certain
feeling
share the feeling of someone else's
sufferings sorrow anger so if you want
to say that you understand how difficult
something may be to another person how
sad he or she may be maybe if you want
to tell your friend I know how angry you
are I understand how you're feeling you
can say I sympathize with you
moving on so Kelly tries to make him
feel better and she says I sympathize
with you I feel for you I know that it's
really difficult and he says I need the
sympathy really I do and then he asks do
you like doing things outdoors
in the spring
let's see what Kelly said yes or yeah
absolutely I love jogging
I just like going for walks so here's
jogging go for a walk or go for walks
it's so beautiful
there's so much to see and that's the
cool thing about living in this city
that's what's so wonderful about living
in the city that's the cool thing about
living in the city now Peter says that's
true and I love being outdoors and
exercising why because I hate the gym
uh-huh
why does he hate the gym he explains I
have a grudge against the gym
Grudge itself let's take a look at this
word here Grudge
g-r-u-d-g-e I think there even was a
film that was titled Grudge although it
was pronounced totally differently it's
Grudge uh uh sound grunge now grunge is
a feeling of dislike okay towards
somebody that continues on for a long
time it's not anger that you have
towards someone for a short time but say
for example somebody said something to
you or maybe betrayed you and you are so
angry with this person for a very long
time for years for example you can have
a grudge against that person or hold a
grudge against that person it basically
means to continuously dislike or have a
feeling of anger towards somebody or
something
Cabin Fever
Kelly says Cabin Fever that's right what
is Cabin Fever
okay fever when do you get a fever a
high temperature when we get sick right
what's cabin cabin is like a cottage
let's say a house not very big rather
like a log house up in the mountains
when you go hiking so Cabin Fever is
something that people experience it's
when you spend so much time indoors or
in a small place for a long time you
often feel anxiety and you feel like
you're going to you're going to go crazy
it's a very uncomfortable feeling and
that is Cabin Fever now what does Peter
say he says yeah I don't like sweating
with a load of other people in the room
so he doesn't like to sweat with so many
people so spring gives me the
opportunity to what to just get into The
Great Outdoors get into meaning go
outside to enjoy the great outdoors
and breathe in some fresh air so he's
talking about breathing in the fresh air
and of course enjoying the outdoors
especially in the spring season okay
that about wraps it up for today's
actual talk conversation let's take a
listen to it one more time
I can't tell you how happy I am to see
winter going oh me too I hate winter
especially in Korea because Korea is
like a country of extremes you know in
the winter it is freezing cold and in
the summer it's baking hot Autumn and
spring they're so short but they're my
favorites oh tell me about it well for
me it's it's kind of a love-hate
relationship with spring
allergies attack oh have you got hay
fever no actually I'm a bit of a weird
case here
um this is gonna sound weird but every
year I suffer from really bad allergies
and yet every time I take an allergy
test my doctor can't figure out what it
is that's causing my hives or my
problems I know but I'm willing to live
with it if it means that I can
comfortably jog outside enjoy the cherry
blossoms and enjoy the beauty of Korean
spring yeah the spring here is so
beautiful but I I'm the same as you I
suffer from allergies but I got hay
fever so I know what it is at least
um I heard that's pretty nasty yeah I
have to take my antihistamines every day
like when it's pollen season and things
like that but I found that less people
in Korea suffer with hay fever than in
the UK like I reckon out of my friends
about half suffer with hay fever but
here not many people do so they didn't
really sympathize with me when my nose
is running or my eyes are itching I
sympathize with you I need it really I
did sorry for you I understand but do
you like doing things outdoors then in
the spring because the winter you can
barely do anything oh yeah I love
jogging you know what I just like going
for walks it's so beautiful
um there's so much to see and that's a
cool thing about living in a city is
that you never get tired because there's
always a new neighborhood to visit right
that's true yeah and I love being
outdoors and exercising because I hate
the gym I have a growth against the gym
because I don't have cabin fever yeah I
don't like sweating with a load of other
people so spring gives me the
opportunity to just get into The Great
Outdoors and breathe some fresh air yeah
cheers to Spring absolutely come on
foreign
welcome back everyone it's time for
actual Expressions let's check out these
words we have in front of us extremes
also known as extremities as you see a
synonym Peaks now Peaks notice
there's an S everywhere which means it's
not just one but if something is
extremely different from each other very
different
you can say extremes all right what
about love hate there was love hate
relationship a synonym for love hate I
think is Bittersweet Bittersweet it
involves two very different emotions and
feelings so when you really like
something but at the same time hate it
you can say love hates something what
about nasty nasty can mean awful tough
or unpleasant sometimes even ugly and
dirty keep that in mind and it's once
again informal reckon means to assume or
to consider think of as and finally
Grudge it's not Grudge it's Grudge
grunge and it means bitterness hatred or
dislike all right now that we're done
with these vocab words let's now
continue on with our patterns live with
it is what we heard in today's actual
talk right to live with something means
to just accept it because there's
nothing you can do to change it you have
no choice hey live with it here we go
with a sample sentence I've decided to
live with it
accepted and get on with my life without
him move on
keep living my life without it okay
I hate my haircut
but I guess I have no other choice but
to live with it accept it got it all
right let's now move on to sympathize
with someone about someone or something
that sympathize with means to understand
somebody else's suffering sorrow anger
feelings okay
I sympathize with you
about the difficulties you're going
through so this sentence means I
understand how difficult this may be for
you I understand I feel for you I
sympathize with you what about this one
my parents sympathized with me but they
didn't know how to help me this happens
sometimes you really understand the
trouble and the hardships the sorrow the
anger the pain somebody is going through
but there's nothing you can do to help
them in that case you can say somebody
sympathized with me but they did not
know how to help me moving on to our
final pattern bear hold or have a grudge
against someone this is a feeling of
dislike that continues on for a long
time
he has a grudge against me why because I
refused to date him
I said no I'm not going to date you no
thank you I don't like you but he was so
hurt he continued to hate me for a very
long time okay in that case you can have
hold or bear a grudge against someone
one last one I'm not the type to hold
grudges against people okay so if you're
the cool type you don't let things
bother you somebody's mean to you okay
that's fine if you're cool you can say
I'm not the type to hold grudges against
people all right everyone job all done
[Music]
spring I love spring when the seasons
change and you know winter is such a
cold dry experience I don't really enjoy
winter very much so when Spring weather
comes and the temperature rises the days
get longer I it's just really a good
feeling you know I when I was younger I
used to play basketball and in the
spring it would be maybe zero degrees
Celsius and I would be outside in shorts
just because it feels so warm my mom
would always yell at me to come back
inside you know spring is also the time
when the flowers come back out the
leaves come out it's the season of
renewal Rebirth of course with that
comes allergies so that's kind of a
bummer itself I have slight allergies
get a little bit of runny nose but
spring is also the time for new baseball
games to go to to go to the the Han
River and just have a picnic and I
really enjoy getting out there in the
spring it's really one of my favorite
times of the year
[Music]
well in today's
weather but also some activities you can
enjoy as well that's right baseball he's
mentioned here we go I love spring
when the seasons change okay when the
seasons change for example from Winter
to spring and winter is such a cold dry
experience we can sense that winter is
not his favorite season when Spring
weather comes approaches nears and the
temperature rises when the temperature
goes up days get longer it's just really
a good feeling
he likes all these things about spring
the leaves come out too the leaves grow
from trees they turn green they grow it
is the season of renewal or we can also
call it rebirth everything is born again
it's a fresh new start and that's
exactly what he's saying well Alex
mentioned something about how spring is
also the time for new baseball games to
go to which is very exciting as well
alright thanks Alex jobs job well done
spring I love spring when the seasons
change and you know winter is such a
cold dry experience I don't really enjoy
winter very much so when Spring weather
comes and the temperature rises the days
get longer I it's just really a good
feeling you know I when I was younger I
used to play basketball and in the
spring it would be maybe zero degrees
Celsius and I would be outside in shorts
just because it feels so warm my mom
would always yell at me to come back
inside you know spring is also the time
when the flowers come back out the
leaves come out it's the season of
renewal Rebirth of course with that
comes allergies so that's kind of a
bummer itself I have slight allergies
get a little bit of runny nose but
spring is also the time for new baseball
games to go to to go to the the Han
River and just have a picnic and I
really enjoy getting out there there in
the spring it's really one of my
favorite times of the year
[Music]
well time is up everyone and I'm going
to have to say goodbye but today we
talked about spring weather next time
let's talk about something that comes
near us during this season an Uninvited
Guest will talk about yellow dust or
yellow sandals so we'll figure out and
find out what you can say the next time
you happen to talk about that topic what
you can do is come to our home page come
on over to
www.ebse.co.kr and look for actual
English with Jennifer just leave us some
comments once you swing by even a short
hello is welcome as well okay everyone
that is all for today I'll catch you
again next time bye for now
foreign
[Music]